Preliminary Inventory to the Rita Ricardo-Campbell Papers, 1964-1980
Hoover Institution Archives
Rita Ricardo-Campbell Papers,
1964-2004
78039
Ricardo-Campbell, Rita
47 manuscript boxes, 1 videotape cassette (18.4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter, relating to the administration and financing of higher education, the Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, the Mountain States Regional Medical Program, and the National Center for Higher Education Management Systems
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1978.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biography/Adminstrative History
An american economist and educator as well as a senior fellow at the Hoover Institution, Ricardo-Campbell specialized in the health care sector and the economic and political problems of the Social Security system. She was for two years the Chairman of the Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, for twelve years a director of the Gillette Company, for twenty-one years a director of the Watkins Johnson Company, and until recently a director of the Samaritan Medical Management Group. A native of Boston, Massachusetts, Ricardo-Campbell received a bachelor of science degree from Simmons College and master's and Ph.D. degrees from Harvard University.
Scope and Content of Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, and printed matter, relating to the administration and financing of higher education, the Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education, the Mountain States Regional Medical Program, and the National Center for Higher Education Management Systems
Access Points
Mountain States Regional Medical Program; National Center for Higher Education Management Systems; Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education; Education; Education--United States; Medical education--United States; Universities and colleges--United States; United States; Video tapes
PRELIMINARY INVENTORY
- Correspondence files, A-H, with detailed index in first folder (Box 1-3)
- Correspondence files, I-MTGS, 1967-1971 August (Box 4-6)
- Correspondence files, Meetings-NCHEMS (Box 7-9)
- Correspondence files, No-Z (Box 10-12)
- Annual reports, 1966-1974; This is WICHE, 1966-1976, 1976; The Inside, 1972-1976 March; WICHE calendar; Source book: com'ners, staff, program, etc.; Reports on Higher Education; Impact reports, 1968-1972 (Box 13-15)
- WICHE, meeting agenda, 1966-1975 August (Box 16-18)
- Higher education; booklets on correctional institutions; rehabilitation manpower; social work education; post-secondary education (Box 19-21)
- Medical, including: mental health, nursing, psychiatrists-teachers; drug addiction; veterinarians, etc. (Box 22-24)
- Mountain state (regional) medical programs (Box 25-26)
- NCHEMS (National Center for Higher Education Management Systems at WICHE) (Box 27-29)
  - 1968-1971
  - 1972-1976 (Box 30-32)
- Higher Education and National Affairs, American Council on Education, 1970-75 (Box 33)
- Books, reports, other printed matter relating to financing and administering higher education. Reports, 1970-73. Ford Foundation Program for research in University Administration; Office of the Vice President - Planning, University of California (Box 34-35)
- Invitations by the Committee for the American Bicentennial Presidential Inauguration to the inauguration of George Bush and Dan Quayle on January 20, 1989 (Box 36)
- WICHE (Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education), 1978-80 (Box 36)
- Writings, Speeches, Interviews, 1985-1996 (Box 37-39)
  - 1985-1989 (Box 37)
  - 1990-1992 (Box 38)
  - 1992-1996 (Box 39)
    Includes video tapes.
- Conference on Inflation Agenda and notes, Washington D.C, September 1974 (Box 40)
- Speeches and Writings, 1980-2000 (Box 41)
- Mt. Pelerin Society, 1980 (Box 41)
- Speeches and Writings, 1992-1993 (Box 42)
- Resisting Hostile Takeovers: The Case of Gillette files, circa 1995-1997 (Box 43)
- Resisting Hostile Takeovers: The Case of Gillette files, circa 1995-1997 (Box 44)
- Other publications by Rita Ricardo-Campbell, 1980s-1990s (Box 44)
- Research file: Alexander Solzhenitsyn (Box 44)
- Writings, drafts (Box 45)
- Health Care Writings, book drafts, research, 1980s-1990s (Box 46)
- Health Care research, 1980s-1990s. (Box 47)
  Includes audio cassettes.